这是普通高等学校招生全国统一考试
英语科听力部分。
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意，回答听力部分时。
请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到客观题答题卡上。
I read about your club in the paper today, and I thought I'd phone to find out a bit
more. Yes, certainly.
Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different countries.
It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
What kinds of events do you organise?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day, except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to my French.
OK. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form and
some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
请看听力部分第一节。
第一节，听下面五段对话。
每段对话后有一个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完每段对话后。
你都有十秒钟的时间，来回答有关小题和
阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如：现在你有五秒钟的时间看。
试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容：
Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有五秒钟的时间。
将正确答案画在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，
所以你选择
项，并将其画在试卷上。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间
阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Do you have any plans for the weekend, Dorothy?
Would you like to join me for an outing?
Thanks, but I'm going to work on my paper all weekend.
So, what did you buy?
A T -shirt.
It was a bargain.
I got it half price, saving 15 dollars.
I'm going to the museum Sunday afternoon.
There's a new exhibition of Indian art.
Want to come with me?
I'd love to, but my best friend is getting married on Sunday, and I won't miss it
for anything. National Bank, can I help you?
Yes, please. What are your business hours?
open at nine and close at four during the week.
On Saturday, we close one hour earlier at three, and we're closed on Sunday.
May I help you, sir?
Yes, I seem to have lost my room key.
In that case, you'll need to go to the front desk to get another one.
第一节到此结束。
第二节。
听下面五段。
对话或独白。
每段对话或独白后有几个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白。
读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答
第六和第七两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Hello, Nora? I heard about a flat that might interest you girls.
It's near the central bus station on the main road, and about 75 pounds a week.
Quite reasonable. The problem is, it's only got two bedrooms, but I expect two of
could share. Well, as long as it isn't me, I've got to my own room, because I'd be
working at home most of the time.
Any other information?
Yes, it's got a very big and well -equipped kitchen, and I know you like cooking, so
that's another point in its favor.
But there's a small sitting room, and not much furniture yet, so let me know quickly
if you want it, or it'll be taken.
Hello, Nora? I heard about a flat that might interest you girls.
It's near the central bus station on the main road, and about 75 pounds a week.
Quite reasonable. The problem is, it's only got two bedrooms, but I expect two of
you could share.
Well, as long as it isn't me, I've got to have my own room, because I'd be working
at home most of the time.
Any other information?
Yes, it's got a very big and well -equipped kitchen, and I know you like cooking, so
that's another point in its favor.
But there's a small sitting room, and not much furniture yet, so let me know quickly
if you want it, or it'll be taken.
听下面一段对话，回答
第八和第九两个小题。
现在，你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题
a big -equipped taken.
Hello, Barbara. Welcome back.
You look great.
Rod, it's lovely to see you again.
How was your trip?
Fun, but tiring.
Milan was interesting.
It's bigger than I expected.
Noisier and dirtier, too.
And Florence? What did you think of Florence?
Well, I didn't go there.
Have you been there?
No, I've never been to Italy.
I'd really like to go to Rome.
Well, the car's in the car park.
Is this all your luggage?
Yes, but the suitcase is very heavy.
Barbara, what's in it?
Books? Or stones?
Just twenty pairs of shoes.
Hello, Barbara. Welcome back.
You look great.
Hello, Barbara, what's in it?
Books? Or stones?
Just twenty pairs of Barbara, what's in
Books? Answer three
听下面一段对话，回答
第十至第十二三个。
小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Is there by any chance?
I'm afraid not.
He's away for a day or two.
Back on, let's see, Monday morning.
Oh, well, perhaps I can leave a message for him.
Yes, of course.
Just a minute.
Now, let's see.
To Jack Cooper from Mike London.
No, Landon. L -A -N -D -O -N.
Sorry. Yes, got that.
And what's the message?
Well, it's just this.
Could he come to a meeting on Monday afternoon at 5 p.m.?
That's this coming Monday, October 12th?
Right. It's to discuss the new factory in France.
Fine. I've got that.
I'll see that he gets it as soon as he comes in on Monday.
Good. Thank you.
Goodbye. Hello, Thomas Brothers.
Hello. This is Mike Landon here.
Is Jack Cooper there by any chance?
I'm afraid not.
He's away for a day or two.
Back on, let's see, Monday morning.
Oh, well, perhaps I can leave a message for him.
Yes, of course.
Just a minute.
Now, let's see.
To Jack Cooper from Mike London.
No, Landon. L -A -N -D -O -N.
Sorry. Yes, got that.
And what's the message?
Well, it's just this.
Could he come to a meeting on Monday afternoon at 5 p.m.?
That's coming Monday, October 12th?
Right. It's to discuss the new factory in France.
Fine. I've got that.
I'll see that he gets it as soon as he comes in on Monday.
Good. Thank you.
听下面一段对话。
回答第十三至第十六四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
Now, What What What is
Now, Mrs. Franks, I'd like to read your statement back to you, and then you can
write your name on it.
Fine. What is it?
That's correct. Now, Mrs.
Franks, I'd just like to read your statement back to you, and then you can write
your name on it.
Fine. That's correct.
Mrs. just like read
听下面一段独白，回答
第十七至第二十四个小题。
现在。你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
Welcome to Montfort School.
Thank you for choosing our school and for joining the happy Montfort family, which
has been educating boys since 1916.
We are so happy that you have taken time off to be with us today.
It is with great pleasure that we have prepared some events that we hope will please
you. At 9 a.m., our headmaster will give a welcome speech.
This will be in the school hall.
Please be seated by 8.45 a.m.
Following the speech is the guided tour of the exhibition at 9.30.
Here you can see the proud history of our school and our achievements in the field
of education. The exhibition is laid out in the classrooms on the second floor.
Then the guided tour of science labs at 10.20 a.m.
Here you can see the subjects that new students will be studying.
You will also notice that our labs have excellent equipment.
At 11 a.m., you'll be guided to the tour to practical areas.
This covers our technical workshops, music, and other areas of our school life.
At Montfort, we believe in all -round development of our students.
Lunch will be at 12.
It has been specially prepared for our guests.
All our teachers and student leaders will be present to answer any questions that
you have in your minds.
We are so happy that you could be with us today.
Welcome to Montfort School.
Thank you for choosing our school and for joining the happy Montfort family, which
has been educating boys since 1916.
We are so happy that you have taken time off to be with us today.
It is with great pleasure that we have prepared some events that we hope will please
you. At 9 a.m., our headmaster will give a welcome speech.
This will be in the school hall.
Please be seated by 8.45 a.m.
Following the speech is the guided tour of the exhibition at 9.30.
Here you can see the proud history of our school and our achievements in the field
of education. The exhibition is laid out in the classrooms on the second floor.
Then the guided tour of science labs at 10.20 a.m.
Here you can see the subjects that new students will be studying.
You will also notice that our labs have excellent equipment.
At 11 a.m., you'll be guided to the tour to practical areas.
This covers our technical workshops, music, and other areas of our school life.
At Montfort, we believe in all -round development of our students.
Lunch will be at 12.
It has been specially prepared for our guests.
All our teachers and student leaders will be present to answer any questions that
you have in your minds.
We are so happy that you could be with us today.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案
转涂到客观题答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. you.
听力部分。
到此结束。